RENÉE CRUZ

(646) 704-8919 | reneebasscruz@gmail.com | Linkedin | Github | Blog | Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Web Developer experienced with Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming. Proven track record in the music industry as a performer and a product manager. I live at the intersection of technical expertise and artistic excellence to help visionary companies build brand legacy, drive revenue and to create lasting impact.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6+), Ruby, Rails, SQL/SQLite, Postgres, React, React Hooks, React Router, Redux, JWT Auth, Version Control (Glt/Github), Active Record, REST API, RESTful Architecture, HTML, CSS, Sinatra, MVC, OOP

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Small Shop - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo | Deployed Web App

Online Shop Web App for e-commerce entrepreneurs provides secure functionality to persist user's cart and account.

- Authorized users via JSON Web Tokens and localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side for login and perisit functionality
- Built Backend API using Ruby on Rails and RESTular for user database, order logic, and perform CRUD actions
- Implemented React JS to create reusable UI components for modularity and dynamic routing using React-Router
- Utilized Redux to create a single source of truth in handling persistence of the user's account and cart logic
- Employed REST Client to query data structures from H&M Inventory API to populate items model in the backend

Horacle | Horoscope Oracle for Madlibs Astrology - <u>Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo | Deployed Web App</u> Interactive Oracle prompt co-creates a user's future by choosing words for fun and generating a random prediction.

- Generated random Madlib data by GET request to RESTFUL Rails API backend, used Ruby & JS for logic wordbank
- Created an interactive UI using pure CSS to enable a toggle switch for the user to between light and dark mode
- Implemented Fetch to guery and retrieve data from external Horoscope & Astrology API to render daily horoscope
- Established a link to Twitter API to publish user's generated madlib horoscope on their individual Twitter account

Doggo Doption - Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

Pet adoption web app connects users to their new best friends and allows them virtual adoption in their secure account.

- Implemented React JS and React Router to create unique URLs & UI composed of reusable components
- Utilized JSON Web Token Authentication, BCrypt and localStorage to authenticate and authorize the user
- Fetched data from Dog CEO API and incorporated Faker Gem to generate dog data to Frontend
- Built Backend API using Ruby on Rails and designed database schema using Active Record and Postgres DB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer, **Gramercy Tech**, New York, NY

06/2020 - Present

Engineer custom UI and functionality for the Eventfinity team virtual events platform, clients include Fortune 500s

Accompanist, The Juilliard School, New York, NY

03/2016 - Present

Sight-read music notation during live performances on double bass for International festival audience of thousands

Growth Lead, Feldor Billiards Inc. DBA Fat Cat & Fat Cat Fab Lab, New York, NY

12/2008 - 03/201

- Increased revenue from low 100K to over 5M from 2011 to 2016 by leveraging connections and marketing for live music, cultural events & educational initiatives, designed and managed website, HTML, CSS, Adobe Creative Cloud
- Established Fabrication Lab community maker space by R&D, providing access to digital fabrication tools for rapid prototyping, designed and managed website HTML, CSS, Wordpress, FTP, hosting, email marketing, social media
- Originated membership by implementing marketing strategy through community events, curriculum & classes

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, New York
Software Engineering Immersive
The Juilliard School, New York, New York
Master of Music (MM)
The New School, New York, New York
Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA)

08/2019 - 12/2019

08/2005 - 05/2007

01/2001 - 05/2004